The great adventure of a king who defied the odds to prove himself a man.
Henry V is a war, drama, history film directed by Kenneth Branagh.
In 1415, in the midst of the Hundred Years' War, the young King
Henry V of England embarks on the conquest of France.
Henry V, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Chorus, played by Derek Jacobi.
Exeter, played by Brian Blessed.
Bedford, played by James Larkin.
French King, played by Paul Scofield.
Katherine, played by Emma Thompson.
Henry V is a 1989 British historical drama film written and directed by Kenneth Branagh in his
feature directorial debut, based on William Shakespeare's history play of the same name.
It stars Branagh in the title role of King Henry V of England, with Paul Scofield, Derek Jacobi, Ian Holm, Brian
Blessed, Emma Thompson, Alec McCowen, Judi Dench, Robbie Coltrane, and Christian Bale in supporting roles.
Henry V received widespread critical acclaim and is considered one of
the best Shakespeare screen adaptations ever produced.
Among its numerous accolades, the film received three nominations at the 62nd Academy
Awards, two of which went to Branagh (Best Director and Best Actor).
Henry V won with its other nomination, Best Costume Design for Phyllis Dalton.
The film explores themes of france, kingdom, theater play,
based on true story, based on play or musical.
The tone is emotional.